A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1952
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1952
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.591
This collection consists of 11,400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1959 January 14.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files, 1952
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 1)
  - Academic Organization 1952 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1952 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Office 1952 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) 1952 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--A 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--B 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--C 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--D 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--E 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--F 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--G 1952 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions--H 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--I 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--J 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--K 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--L 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--M 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--N 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--O 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--P 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--R 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--S 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--T 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--U 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--V 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--W 1952 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions--X,Y,Z 1952 (Box 2)
  - Army--General 1952 (Box 2)
  - Army Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC)--Transportation Corps 1952 (Box 2)
  - Army ROTC--Medical Corps 1952 (Box 2)
  - Army--Judge Advocate General's Office 1952 (Box 2)
  - Art and Architecture 1952 (Box 2)
  - Art Commission 1952 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU) 1952 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges (AAC) 1952 (Box 2)
  - Association of Land-Grant Colleges (ALGC) 1952 (Box 2)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges (AVC) 1952 (Box 2)
  - Astronomy 1952 (Box 2)
  - Athletics 1952 Jan-Jun (Box 2)
  - Athletics 1952 Jul-Dec (Box 3)
  - Athletics--National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) 1952 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--Commonwealth Day 1952 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--Intramurals 1952 (Box 3)
  - Atlantic Union 1952 (Box 3)
  - Attorney General 1952 (Box 3)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1952 (Box 3)
  - "Ba-Bl" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 4)
  - "Bm-Bz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 4)
  - Bibliographical Society 1952 (Box 4)
  - Biology 1952 (Box 4)
  - Biology--Mountain Lake 1952 (Box 4)
  - Biology--Blandy Farm 1952 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds--General 1952 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Academic Building 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Cemetery 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Chemistry 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Commons 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Electricity 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Gas 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Roads 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Telephone System 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--General 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Architects and Engineers 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Contracts 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Convalescent Children's Home 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Law Department 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Life Science Building 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Medical Buildings 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Men's Dormitories 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Natural Resources Building 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Naval Armory 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Physics Building 1952 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Power Plant and Heating Main 1952 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Site Plans 1952 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Student Activities Building 1952 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Women's Dormitory 1952 (Box 6)
  - Bursar's Office 1952 (Box 6)
  - Byrd, Senator H. F. 1952 (Box 6)
  - "Ca-Ck" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 6)
  - "Cl-Cz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 6)
  - Caps and Gowns 1952 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1952 (Box 7)
  - Cavalier Daily 1952 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry 1952 (Box 7)
  - Civilian Defense 1952 (Box 7)
  - Classics 1952 (Box 7)
  - Clippings 1952 (Box 7)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1952 (Box 7)
  - Commerce and Economics 1952 (Box 7)
  - Academic Legislation Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Administrative Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Administrative Policy Committee of the University of Virginia Hospital 1952 (Box 8)
  - Admissions--College 1952 (Box 8)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Board Committees 1952 (Box 8)
  - Chaperones' Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Committee for a Free Asia 1952 (Box 8)
  - Hospital Administrative Policy Committee (Empty) 1952 (Box 8)
  - Instate of Public Affairs Advisory Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Lectures Committees 1952 (Box 8)
  - Lower Division Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Committees 1952 (Box 8)
  - New Committee Material (Empty) 1952 (Box 8)
  - Processions Committee (Empty) 1952 (Box 8)
  - Public Occasions Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Rushton Seminars Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Scholarships, Loans, and Employment Committee 1952 (Box 8)
  - Science Advisory Committee 1952 (Box 9)
  - Senate Reorganization Committee 1952 (Box 9)
  - Social Security Committee for Faculty 1952 (Box 9)
  - Tree Committee 1952 (Box 9)
  - Women's Dormitory Name Committee (Empty) 1952 (Box 9)
  - Compulsory Education 1952 (Box 9)
  - Compulsory Education--Clippings 1952 (Box 9)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1952 (Box 9)
  - Council of State Governments 1952 (Box 10)
  - "Da-Dd" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 10)
  - "De-Dz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 10)
  - Development Fund 1952 Jul-Dec (Box 11)
  - Development Fund 1952 Jan-Jun (Box 11)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 11)
  - Education 1952 (Box 11)
  - Endowment--Alumni Board of Trustees 1952 (Box 12)
  - Endowment--Contingent Fund 1952 (Box 12)
  - Education School--Proposal for and Audio-Visual Research Center-- (Missing) 1952 (Box 12)
  - Engineering Department 1952 (Box 12)
  - English 1952 (Box 12)
  - Extension Division 1952 (Box 12)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 13)
  - Faculty 1952 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--General 1952 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Bayly-Tiffany Scholarships 1952 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Ford Foundation Fellowship 1952 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Fulbright Awards 1952 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Rhodes Scholarships 1952 (Box 13)
  - Finals 1952 (Box 13)
  - Fletcher, R. R. 1952 (Box 14)
  - Food Services 1952 (Box 14)
  - Foreign Affairs 1952 (Box 14)
  - Founder's Day 1952 (Box 14)
  - Forestry 1952 (Box 14)
  - Forms and Form Letters 1952 (Box 14)
  - Fraternities 1952 (Box 14)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1952 (Box 14)
  - Gifts and Grants--Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 15)
  - Gifts and Grants--Development Fund 1952 (Box 15)
  - Gifts and Grants--Approval of (Governor's Office) 1952 (Box 15)
  - Garden Club 1952 (Box 15)
  - General Education Board 1952 (Box 15)
  - Geography 1952 (Box 15)
  - Geology 1952 (Box 15)
  - Germanic Languages 1952 (Box 15)
  - Governor's Office 1952 (Box 15)
  - Graduate Department 1952 (Box 16)
  - "Ha--He" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 16)
  - "Hf-Hz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 16)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1952 (Box 16)
  - History 1952 (Box 16)
  - Honors Courses 1952 (Box 16)
  - Honor System 1952 (Box 16)
  - Hospital 1952 Jul-Dec (Box 16)
  - Hospital 1952 Jan-Jun (Box 17)
  - Hospital--Blue Cross 1952 (Box 17)
  - Hospital--Medical Board, minutes of meeting 1952 (Box 17)
  - Hospital--Monthly Statistical Reports 1952 (Box 17)
  - Housing 1952 (Box 17)
  - Housing--Faculty Housing on Lawn and Grounds (see "University Houses") 1952 (Box 17)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 17)
  - India 1952 (Box 17)
  - Institute of International Education 1952 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations 1952 (Box 17)
  - Insurance 1952 (Box 18)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1952 (Box 18)
  - International Association of Universities (IAU) 1952 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--A 1952 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--B 1952 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--C 1952 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--D 1952 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--E 1952 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--F 1952 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--G 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--H 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--I 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--J 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--K 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--L 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--M 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--N 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--O 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--P 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--Q 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--R 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--S 1952 (Box 19)
  - Invitations--T 1952 (Box 20)
  - Invitations--U 1952 (Box 20)
  - Invitations--V 1952 (Box 20)
  - Invitations--W 1952 (Box 20)
  - Invitations--X, Y, Z 1952 (Box 20)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 20)
  - Japan International Christian University 1952 (Box 20)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation (TJMF) 1952 (Box 20)
  - Judge Advocate General's Office (see "Army") 1952 (Box 20)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 20)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 20)
  - Law School 1952 (Box 21)
  - Lectures--General 1952 (Box 21)
  - Lectures--Page-Barbour Lectures 1952 (Box 21)
  - Lectures--Richard Lectures 1952 (Box 21)
  - Legal Matters 1952 (Box 21)
  - Legislative Program 1952 (Box 21)
  - Library 1952 (Box 21)
  - Library--MacGregor Library 1952 (Box 21)
  - Library--Board of Alderman 1952 (Box 21)
  - Loan Funds 1952 (Box 21)
  - Lower Division of the College 1952 (Box 21)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 22)
  - McIntyre Fund 1952 (Box 22)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 22)
  - "Mf-Mz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 22)
  - Madison Hall 1952 (Box 22)
  - Marine Corps 1952 (Box 22)
  - Mary Washington College 1952 (Box 22)
  - Mary Washington Dockets 1952 (Box 22)
  - Mathematics 1952 (Box 23)
  - Medical Department 1952 (Box 23)
  - Samuel Miller Fund 1952 (Box 23)
  - Military--Miscellaneous (see also "Army", "Navy", "Marine Corps", etc.) 1952 (Box 23)
  - Music 1952 (Box 23)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 23)
  - National Association of State Universities (NASU) 1952 (Box 23)
  - National Commission of Accrediting (NCA) 1952 (Box 23)
  - National Education Association (NEA) 1952 (Box 23)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) 1952 (Box 23)
  - Naval ROTC 1952 (Box 23)
  - Navy 1952 (Box 23)
  - Newcomb, J. L. 1952 (Box 23)
  - Naval ROTC--Printed and mimeographed communications (Empty) 1952 (Box 23)
  - Nursing Education 1952 (Box 23)
  - Nursing School 1952 (Box 23)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 24)
  - Oak Ridge 1952 (Box 24)
  - "Pa-Pe" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 24)
  - "Pf-Pz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 24)
  - Patents 1952 (Box 24)
  - Personnel 1952 (Box 24)
  - Personnel--Retirement Bill 1952 (Box 24)
  - Personnel and Placement Office 1952 (Box 24)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1952 (Box 24)
  - Philosophy 1952 (Box 24)
  - Physical Education 1952 (Box 24)
  - Physics 1952 (Box 24)
  - Political Science 1952 (Box 24)
  - President's Council 1952 (Box 24)
  - Pritchett, M. E. 1952 (Box 25)
  - Psychology 1952 (Box 25)
  - Purchase and Printing--State Office 1952 (Box 25)
  - Purchase Office 1952 (Box 25)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 25)
  - Questionnaires 1952 (Box 25)
  - Questionaires-- Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 25)
  - Radio 1952 (Box 25)
  - Raven Society 1952 (Box 25)
  - Recommendations, Letters of 1952 (Box 25)
  - Regional Education 1952 (Box 25)
  - Registrar 1952 (Box 25)
  - Religion 1952 (Box 25)
  - Requisitions 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--General 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--Army Research 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--Bureau of Public Administration 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--Geographical Institute 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--Medical Research 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--National Research Council 1952 (Box 26)
  - Research--Naval Research 1952 (Box 26)
  - Richmond Area University Center 1952 (Box 26)
  - Romance Languages 1952 (Box 26)
  - Rural Social Economics 1952 (Box 26)
  - "Sa-Sl" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 27)
  - "Sm-Sz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 27)
  - Salaries 1952 (Box 27)
  - Segregation 1952 (Box 27)
  - Selective Service 1952 (Box 27)
  - Senate-- University 1952 (Box 27)
  - Sigma Xi 1952 (Box 27)
  - Social Security 1952 (Box 27)
  - Sociology 1952 (Box 27)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (SACSS) 1952 (Box 28)
  - Southern University Conference 1952 (Box 28)
  - Speeches and Articles 1952 (Box 28)
  - Speech and Drama 1952 (Box 28)
  - State Board of Education 1952 (Box 28)
  - State Board of Health 1952 (Box 28)
  - State University Association (SUA) 1952 (Box 28)
  - Statistics 1952 (Box 28)
  - Student Aid Office 1952 (Box 28)
  - Student Health Department 1952 (Box 28)
  - Sullivan Award 1952 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session 1952 (Box 28)
  - Surplus Property 1952 (Box 28)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 28)
  - Television 1952 (Box 28)
  - Travel 1952 (Box 28)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1952 (Box 29)
  - Treasury Department 1952 (Box 29)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 29)
  - United States Office of Education 1952 (Box 29)
  - University News Service 1952 (Box 29)
  - University Press 1952 (Box 29)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 29)
  - Veterans 1952 (Box 29)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1952 (Box 29)
  - Virginia Education Association 1952 (Box 29)
  - Virginia Institute for Scientific Research 1952 (Box 29)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1952 (Box 29)
  - Board of Visitors--Correspondence 1952 (Box 29)
  - Board of Visitors--Dockets 1952 (Box 29)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Anderson 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Judge Darksdale 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Black 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Carrington 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Coxe 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Dr. Emmett 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Garnett 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Howard 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Mears 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mrs. Smith 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Howard Smith 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mr. Talbott 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mrs. Wailes 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Miss Wheeler 1952 (Box 30)
  - Board of Visitors--Mrs. Willis 1952 (Box 30)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 31)
  - "Wi--Wz" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 31)
  - Women, Dean of 1952 (Box 31)
  - "X, Y, Z" Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 31)